Aaron **Goidel Computer Science Student**

☑ aarongoidel.com

@ acgoidel@gmail.com

New York, NY / Toronto, ON

Creative and driven computer science student with loves for learning and problem solving. Experience working in teams creating new technologies; strong leadership and presentations skills, and equally strong technical ability. Interested in machine learning, linguistics, operating systems, and in working to apply computer science to areas of passion, such as law, food, and music.



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

July 2020 Current

Junior Software Engineer | HIGHSNOBIETY

New York, NY

- > Junior Engineer creating a pipeline for retail product data collection
- > Implemented, maintained, and improved upon web scraping and data parsing infrastructure for increased performance in data collection from retail partners—with performance increases of up to 80%
- > Served as an interface between content and engineering teams to prioritize data collection and processing needs
- > Assessed and performed triage for critical systems in real-time

December 2020 April 2020

Product Engineer | MLKMN

Remote

- > Working to create onboarding and backend tools for a small (< 10 employees) startup
- > Coordinate with business leadership to recommend and implement new technologies
- > Manage the technology end of projects related to user onboarding

June 2019 August 2019

Cybersecurity Research Intern | NATIONAL SECURITY AGENCY

Fort Meade, MD

- > Authored a patch in the Linux operating system, implementing a security hook and permissions for controlling file system watches, including corresponding test suite
- > Experimented with machine learning models to estimate the proximity of Bluetooth Low Energy enabled IoT devices in obstructed spaces
- > Presented progress and findings to groups of 20+ researchers in biweekly technical briefings

November 2016 August 2017

Lead Coding Instructor | MONTCLAIR LEARNING CENTER

Montclair, NJ

- > Taught coding in after school and summer programs to primary and middle school aged students
- > Created and executed lesson plans in Scratch, App Inventor, and Python
- > Interfaced with parents on a weekly basis about student's progress
- > Oversaw work done by junior employees



EDUCATION

September 2019 April 2023 (expected)

Current Student | UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO

- > Current second year student seeking a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science with minors in **Pure Mathematics and Linguistics**
- > GPA: 3.91/4.00
- > Technology Officer for the Computer Science Student Community
- > Contributing opinions writer for The Medium (school newspaper)
- > Relevant course work: Theory of Computation, Software Design, Communication Skills for Computer Scientists, Project Management, Syntactic Patterns in Language, Syntax, Data Structures and Analysis, Computer Organization

September 2015 June 2019

High School | MONTCLAIR KIMBERLEY ACADEMY

- > Graduated with a GPA of 3.75/4.0
- > Classes included: AP Physics C, AP Calculus AB, AP Computer Science A, AP Chinese, Data Structures and Algorithms
- > Leadership roles in several organizations including: Mock Trial (lead lawyer and captain), STEM Team (president), School Newspaper (chief digital editor), Committee for Educational Technology

TECHNICAL SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES C, Python, JavaScript (NodeJS, React, React Native), Java, Go

PLATFORMS & TECHNOLOGIES Git (GitHub), Unix Command Line, LaTeX

TECHNICAL SKILLS Agile, Scrum, Web Scraping, OOP, SOLID

SPOKEN LANGUAGES English (native), Mandarin (intermediate)

***** CERTIFICATIONS

U.S. TOP SECRET//SI//TK SECURITY CLEARANCE Including full-scope background investigation, polygraph examination, and psychological evaluation

APPLE CERTIFIED MAC TECHNICIAN

RED CROSS CPR/AED CERTIFIED

THONORS, AWARDS, AND ACHIEVEMENTS

2021 UofT Hack The Case Competition 1^{st} Place

2021 UofT PyJaC Coding Competition Advanced Champion

2019-2020 Dean's List

2019-2020 Math and Computer Science Honour Roll

2019 Montclair Kimberley Academy commencement award in Computer Science

2018 Essex County Mock Trial champion

2017, 2018, 2019 Lockheed Martin Code Quest competition champion (New Jersey, Advanced Division)

2016, 2017, 2018 Agile Youth Hackathon champion

PROJECTS

An online learning community with the aim of eliminating international borders from learning. In a day and a half hackaton, I created a site where tutors and students from all across the globe could connect to exchange knowledge. This is achieved through the use of our very own cryptocurrency, KnowledgeCredits. This was my first introduction to blockchain and I intend to learn much more.

Ethereum React Firebase NextJS

SIMULATING GALAXIES

github.com/AaronCGoidel/n-body

A physics simulation of n particles illustrating the formation of galaxies after a big-bang like event. Written in pure C, this simulation is optimized to faithfully simulate 100,000+ particles on just a laptop.

C OpenGL

SAFESEND

github.com/MKA-Stem/ayc-galvanize

SafeSend utilizes two-factor-authentication and multi-layer encryption to generate secure links to data, ensuring it is only accessible by the intended recipient

JavaScript ReactJS NodeJS Twillio

FSNOTIFY LSM HOOK

Patch on lore.kernel.org/

Implemented a new security check to Security-Enhanced Linux and the Linux Kernel which adds fine-grained control over the setting of watches on file system objects

C SELinux Kernel Linux Security Module

COOKIE

Combining my passions for computer science and food, Cookie is a native smartphone app which applies graph theory to recipes, resulting in a dynamic cookbook. By reimagining recipes as a dependency graph, instead of as a static block of text, Cookie can combine, and simplify recipes to maximize efficiency in the kitchen

React Native Typescript Graph Theory Mobile App